Guide to the Community Service Society Archives
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Charity Organization Society
  - Subseries V.1: Alphabetic Files
    - Casework: (Box 100)
      - Treatment M.E. Richmond (Box 100)
        List of types of situations encountered in practice and the recommended treatment measures. Source of material not indicated - not dated (Presumably around 1911 judging by other content in Folder from which it was taken).
      - Visitors Qualifications. (Box 100)
        Early attempts in developing criteria.
      - Visitors Training 1924-26 (Box 100)
    - Casework & Community Institute, 1929 (Box 101)
      COS material used (auspices American Assn for Organizing Family Social Work now FSAA
    - Catholic Charities COS Cooperation (Box 101)
    - Causes of Distress in Family Life 1898 (Box 101)
    - Central Auxiliary Committee of Ladies (Box 101)
    - Central Bureau (Box 101)
    - Central Council, 1907-1917 (Box 101)
      See Also Boxes 205-211)
    - Reports to central council 11-15-16; 12-5-17 bound bk (Box 101)
    - Reports (1916-1928) in bound book (Box 101)
    - Publicity reports to central council 1916-20 (Box 102)
    - Reports from Social Service Exchange 1915-20 (Box 102)
    - Reports from Central Office Operations 1911-12 (Box 102)
    - Central Financing 1929-32 Covers Welfare Council's Study - Pro & Con Comments (Box 102)
    - Central Office Group See District Secretaries CO Group (Box 103)
    - Chapin - Alumnae Health Bureau See Also: District s - Hudson-Clinton (Box 103)
    - Charities Dispute - 1916 See Also: Charities Review (Box 103)
    - Charities - New York City Conference 1900 (Box 103)
    - Charities Publication 1899-1907 See also: Charities Review (Box 103)
    - Charities - Publications 1900-01 See also: Charities Review (Box 103)
    - Charities - Publication 1904-11 (Valuable data showing the management, development and "trail" of publishing of a social work journal). See also: Charities Review (Box 103)
    - Charity Organization Society - London (Box 103)
    - Charity Rates 1923 (Contains transportation agreements between agencies and states) (Box 103)
    - Charity Rates 1924-29 (Box 104)
    - Charity Rates - Railroad 1905-18 (Box 104)
    - Charity Rates - Railroad 1927-33 (Box 104)
    - Charter and By-laws (Box 104)
    - Child Care – Negro:
      - 1937 Proposal by Welfare Council for a placement study for Negro children and youth. (Box 104)
      - 1935 Study by Welfare Council of provisions for care of Negro boys under 12 adjudged delinquent. (Box 104)
    - Child Labor (Box 104)
    - Child Labor Committee (Formation of the National Child Labor Committee & participation of COS unit) (Box 104)
    - Child Welfare (Box 104)
    - Child Welfare Federation - 1914-29 (Until 1922 known as Babies Welfare Federation Shows agency position in developing services to children) (Box 105)
    - Child Welfare League of America (Box 105)
    - Child Guidance - Bureau of See also: New York School of Social Work (Box 105)
    - Children’s Bureau NYC 1899-1915 (Box 105)
    - Children's Bureau 1914-15 Cases Referred (Box 105)
    - Children's Bureau - United States (Box 105)
    - Children's Court (Box 105)
    - Christmas Giving:[indent]
      - Christmas Dinner Parties Given 1925-26 (Box 105)
      - Christmas Giving by COS Districts 1912-16 (Box 105)
      - Christmas Clearing Bureau 1923 (Box 106)
      - Christmas Dinners 1903-12 (Box 106)
    - Chronically Ill Study by Mary C. Jarrett 1931 See: Welfare Council Chronically Ill Study 1931 (Box 106)
    - Church and Social Work (Box 106)
    - Church and Social Work - Grace Church 1933-38 (Shows the cooperation between COS and Grace Church) (Box 106)
    - Citizens Family Welfare Committee (Box 106)
    - Citizens Family Welfare Committee - 1933 Campaign Radio Skits (Box 106)
    - Citizen s Family Welfare Committee - 1934-35 Campaign Radio Skits (Box 107)
    - Citizens Family Welfare Committee - 1936 Campaign Radio Skits (Box 107)
    - Clinics - Clinton Dental (Box 107)
    - Clinics - Fees Clinics (Box 107)
    - Yorkville Dental:
      - 1916-18 (Box 107)
      - 1919-23 (Box 107)
      - 1924-33 (Box 107)
    - Coal & Fuel Investigation 1898 (Valuable historical data refers to COS investigation of 1898 which resulted in the abolition of outdoor relief by DPC. Opposition to a free coal bill in State legislature) (Box 108)
    - Cocaine, Sale of See: Drug Addiction (Box 108)
    - Committee - Congestion of Population in NYC 1908 (Shows participation of COS in a study concerned with rapid population growth in NYC end inadequate health, recreation, etc. resources.) (Box 108)
    - Committee - Dependent Children (Box 108)
    - Committee - Dispensary Development 1921-26 (Box 108)
    - Committee - Mendicancy - 1901-14 (Box 108)
    - Committee - Mental Hygiene (Shows the varying states of understanding of mental hygiene values among NYC agencies, different patterns of organization to implement use of growing knowledge, etc.) (Box 108)
    - Committee - Mental Hygiene See also: Mental Hygiene & Casework and National Committee on Mental Hygiene (Box 108)
    - Committee - Prevention of Tuberculosis - General Correspondence 1909-1922-1927 (Box 108)
    - Committee - Prevention of Tuberculosis minutes 1907-1914-1919 (Box 109)
    - Committee - Relief Program 1935 (Proposals for a program of Federal Relief) (Box 109)
    - Committee – Research: (Box 109)
    - Minutes 1926-28 (Box 109)
    - General Correspondence (Box 109)
    - Committee - Relief Program See: American Association of Social Workers (Box 109)
    - Committee - Standard of Living (8th NY State Conference of Charities & Correction November 1907) (Box 109)
    - Committee - Standard of Living See also: Costs of Living Detailed material from a study of living costs in NYC in 1907 among working men's families. (Box 109)
    - Committee - Tenement House See: Tenement House Committee (Box 109)
    - Committee - Venereal Disease 1925-1927 (Box 109)
    - Committee of Fourteen 1911-26 (Box 109)
    - Committee on Criminal Courts See also: Courts (Box 109)
    - Committee on the Care of the Poor 1907 Report (Author and agency not known May be useful to one studying treatment of poverty during this period) (Box 109)
    - Committee to study the work of District Committees: See: District Committee to study work of District Committees (Box 109)
    - Community Organization. See: National Social Unit Organization (Box 109)
    - Conference – Monthly (Box 109)
    - Confidentiality. See: Casework: Confidentiality of Records (Box 109)
    - Consolidation Proposals, AICP/COS. See: Merger Proposals, 1894-1919 (Box 110)
    - Constitution (Box 110)
    - Contributors Information Bureau (Box 110)
    - Cooperative Social Settlement Society (Box 110)
    - Cost of Care - Public Institutions, 1897 (Box 110)
    - Cost of Living (Box 110)
    - Courts – Children (Box 110)
    - Courts, Committee on Criminal (Box 110)
    - Courts, Committee on Criminal: (Box 111)
      - 1911-1920 (Box 111)
      - 1923-1928 (Box 111)
      - 1933 - June 1934 (Box 111)
      - 1935 (Box 111)
      - 1936 (Box 112)
      - Minutes, 1910-1936 (Box 112)
      - Reports, etc. (Box 113)
    - Courts – Domestic Relations, New York City (Box 114)
    - Courts, Magistrates (Box 114)
    - Criteria for Position. See: Casework - Visitor in Training (Box 114)
    - Day Care of Children - Survey Proposal, 1917- See: Child Welfare (Box 114)
    - de Forest, Robert Weeks (Box 114)
    - Delinquency. See: Lippincott, Earl (Box 114)
    - Dependent Children 1898-1907
      - Important Historical material re: provisions for care of dependent, neglected and delinquent children. (Box 114)
      - Studies, philosophy expressed by different people. (Box 114)
      - Review of facilities (Box 114)
      - Shows activity of COS in participating on committee in NYC with child care. (Box 114)
    - Dependent Children - Cases 1899
      - Summaries of cases (Box 114)
      - Interesting picture of case load problems of the times and of methods of handling. (Box 114)
    - Depression – 1931-33 (The beginnings of concern about effects of the depression are reflected in minutes of meetings of social workers (COS represented). (Box 115)
    - Depression - Police Cooperation 1930-31 (Box 115)
    - Desertion - 1902-09 (Contains material on a project in which N.J. Palzer of National Desertion Bureau worked with COS on its desertion cases. Shows developing methodology in location work) (Box 115)
    - Detention Facilities for Children 1900 See: Child Welfare (Box 115)
    - Directory of Charities See: Directory of Social Agencies (Box 115)
    - Directory of Social Agencies (Box 115)
    - Disaster Relief - Aid to Defrauded Persons (Box 115)
    - Clark Brothers Relief - 1929 (Box 115)
    - Disaster Relief - Home Services (Box 115)
    - Disaster Relief - Hudson River (Box 115)
    - Disaster Relief - Park Place (Box 116)
    - Disaster Relief - Paterson N. J. Fire & Flood (Box 116)
    - Disaster Relief - Slocum (Box 116)
    - Disaster Relief - Thessalonka (Box 116)
    - Disaster Relief - Titanic (Box 116)
    - Disaster Relief - Volturno (Box 116)
    - Districts. See Also Boxes 198-202. (Box 116)
    - Districts:
      - Boundary Changes (Protests on proposed changes in location, boundaries & consolidation of district offices) (Box 116)
      - Boundary maps 1882-1905 (Box 116)
      - Bronx (Box 116)
      - Chelsea (Box 116)
      - Clinton (Box 116)
      - Committee on Cooperation 1916-23 (Box 117)
      - Committee on District Work 1887-1909 (Box 117)
      - Committee to study the Work of District Committee (Box 117)
      - Committee to Study the Work of (Box 117)
      - Chelsea-Lowell (Box ll8)
      - Corlears (Box ll8)
      - Harlem (Box ll8)
      - Hudson (Box ll8)
      - Hudson-Clinton (See also - Chapin - Alumnae Health Bureau) (Box ll8)
      - Intake Policies (Box ll8)
      - Gramercy (Box ll8)
      - Jefferson (Box ll8)
      - Kips Bay (Box ll8)
      - Riverside (Box ll8)
      - Yorkville "Schermerhorn Park" (This Folder tells a story of how activity of the Yorkville District Committee brought into being as a playground, the present Schermerhorn Park, East 67th & 68th Streets (Box ll8)
      - District Work - Committee on Cooperation (Box ll8)
      - Yorkville (Box ll8)
      - Relief Budgets 1928-34 (Box ll8)
    - District Secretaries-- Central Office Group (Discussions of affairs related to casework operations Responsibility during depression, etc.--This was a sort of steering committee of the Dist. Secy. group):
      - The Work of See: Personalities - Richmond, Mary E. (Box ll8)
      - Meeting 1909 (Box ll8)
      - Called "Agents Meeting" (Box ll8)
      - Meeting -1911-1914 (Box ll8)
      - Meeting - October 1914-June 1915 (Box ll8)
      - Meeting - October 1915-July 1916 (Box 119)
      - Meeting - October 1916-December 1917 (Box 119)
      - Meeting - 1918-1922 (Box 119)
      - Meeting - January 1923-December 1924 (Box 119)
      - Meeting - 1923-1925 (Box 119)
      - Meeting - January 1925-September 1926 (Box 120)
      - Meeting - October 1926-January 1927 (Box 120)
      - Meeting - 1926-1929 (Box 120)
      - Meeting - 1931-1933 (Box 120)
      - Meeting - October 1930-August 1931 (Box 120)
      - Meeting - 1934-35 (Box 120)
      - Meeting - October 1935-July 1938 (Box 120)
    - (Assistants) Meeting October1923-October 1927 (Box 121)
    - (Assistants) - Visitors Meeting 1910-12 (In-Service training and discussion of case practice) (Box 121)
    - Meeting - Work and Procedure 1915 (Box 121)
    - Meeting - Special, 1920-1922 (Box 121)
    - Meeting - Central Office Group (Box 121)
    - Meeting - Program, 1912-1924 (Box 121)
    - Districts - Work and Procedure, 1915 (Box 121)
    - District Work – Reports (Box 121)
    - District Work - Appointment, Visits, Salaries Paid (Mr. Devine Reviews Visits) (Box 121)
    - District Workers 2-day conference (1935 papers) (Box 121)
    - Docket (Box 121)
    - East Harlem Nursing and Health Service - Committee on Education, 1929-1930 (Box 121)
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1921-1922 (Box 121)
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1923-1925 (Box 122)
    - Educational Clinics, 1916-1925 (CCNY-COS Cooperation) (Box 122)
    - Emergency Home Relief Bureau, 1931-1932 (Its development from first stages; Welfare Council Committee material on subject) (Box 122)
    - Emergency Unemployment Relief (Box 122)
    - Employment Bureau for the Handicapped, 1906-1912 (Box 122)
    - Employment Service: (Box 122)
    - COS-Riverside Church (Folder l) (Box 122)
    - Reports, 1931-1933 by May Preuss; 1931-1935 (Box 122)
    - Employment Service - COS-Riverside Church (Folder 2) (Box 122)
    - Eviction Cases, 1914-1915 (Box 124)
    - Eviction Clippings (Box 124)
    - Executive Committee. See: Boxes 212-214. (Box 124)
    - Exhibits:
      - Buffalo, 1903 Paris 1900 (Box 124)
      - World's Fair, St. Louis, 1903 (Box 124)
    - Eye Glasses for School Children (Box 124)
    - Family Agencies - Function of (Box 124)
    - Family Service - Change in Name (Box 124)
    - Family Service: (Box 125)
      - District (Box 125)
      - Secretaries Committee, 1882-1910 (Box 125)
    - Family Welfare Association of Baltimore, 1914-1921 (speeches, etc.) (Box 126)
    - Family Welfare Association of Queens (Box 126)
    - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies (Box 126)
    - Fees for Counseling Services (Box 126)
    - Folks, Homer - Commissioner of Charities See: NYC Charities Dept. of 1898-1903 (Box 126)
    - Forwarding Center Plan 1909-23 (Box 126)
    - Forms - Sample Relief Tickets 1883 (Historical forms data indicating various methods dispensing relief) (Box 126)
    - Fresh Air Fund (Material from 1901-36; Contains information about how COS conducted Fresh Air work and opinions about various kinds of placement used) (Box 126)
    - Fresh Air Home (Describes COS experience in 1919. Summer use of a boarding home on Connecticut shore for groups of mothers and young children for two weeks periods each) (Box 126)
    - Friendly Visitors See: Casework – Friendly Visitors Course by Zilpha D. Smith 1898-99 See also - Mary S Richmond, Notes on 1887 Annual Report (Box 127)
    - Fuel Savings (Box 127)
    - Fund Raising:
      - 1883-1909 (Box 127)
      - Central Financing (Box 127)
      - Central Financing - Protestant Chest Proposal (Box 127)
      - J. P. Jones Plan 1934 (Box 127)
      - Special Appeal (Violin appeal for "Jimmy") (Box 127)
    - German Soap Wrappers -Receipts. See Also Box 308 (Box 127)
    - Gifts in Kind - See:- Thanksgiving Dinners - 1910-1921 (Box 127)
    - Goodwill, Mary C. (Box 127)
    - Paper "Family Re-adjustment After the War" delivered at Atlantic City – undated (Box 127)
    - See Folder: American Red Cross (Box 127)
    - Goodyear, Caroline - Study of 500 Cases 1911-12. See Casework - Caroline Goodyear Study (Box 127)
    - Guardianship (Box 127)
    - Handbooks, (2 volumes) (Box 127)
    - Handbooks, (3 volumes) (Box 128)
    - Harlem Relief Society See Districts - Harlem (Box 128)
    - Harpers Weekly (Attack on COS) See: Press and Social Work (Harpers) (Box 128)
    - Hartsdale Conference April 1911 (Box 128)
    - Hill, Octavia See: COS London, England (Box 128)
    - History – Fifteen Year Chronology COS 1896 Original Copy (Valuable pamphlets and bulletins; Some outside cotemporary articles included to reflect the climate of the times) (Box 128)
    - History - 3 Folder, 2 volumes (Box 128)
    - Hodges, Dean George - 1910 Speech "Practical Philanthropy" See also: American Association for Organizing Family Social Work (Box 129)
    - Home Economics:
      - Budget Standards - 1906 (Box 129)
      - Committee, (2 Folders) (Box 129)
      - Food & Clothing Prices 1919-21 (Box 129)
      - Food Prices (Newspaper Clippings) (Box 129)
      - School Lunches (Box 129)
      - Home Economics and Social Work (Describes content of courses given by home economist (COS) to social workers & information about social science content of curricula for training in home economics) (Box 129)
      - Home Economist 1916 (Box 130)
      - Home Economist 1917-18 (Box 130)
      - Home Economist 1919-26 (Box 130)
      - Home Economist - Budget Study (Box 130)
      - Home Economics - Minutes (Box 130)
      - Home Economics - Monthly Reports 1917-20 (Box 131)
      - Home Economics - Students 1919-21 (Box 131)
    - Home Work (Box 131)
    - Homemaker Service See: Welfare Council - Housekeeping Service Report 1938-43 Also: Visiting Housekeeper Service & Nutrition (Box 131)
    - Homeless:
      - 1927-33 (Box 131)
      - Clippings - Articles (Box 131)
      - Federation of Agencies for Homeless Men 1922-25 (Box 131)
      - Municipal Lodging House 1914-15 (Box 131)
      - Social Service Advisory Committee to Municipal Lodging House (Box 131)
      - Subcommittee - Welfare Council 1927-1929 (Box 132)
      - Subcommittee Welfare Council - Family Section (Box 132)
      - Work Study 1930 (Box 132)
      - Homeless and Unattached Females See: Camp TERA (Box 132)
    - Homemaking Courses (Box 132)
    - Hospitals and Social Service (Describes COS responsibility for investigating ability to pay clinic fees at hospital; describes assistance given to hospitals by COS in setting up social service departments) (Box 133)
    - House of Refuge and House of Detention, 1899-1902 (Box 133)
    - Housing, (7 Folders) (Box 133)
    - Housing, (2 Folders) (Box 134)
    - Immigration Committee - 1899-1902 (Box 134)
    - India House (Box 134)
    - Industrial Development Studies 1896-1931 (Box 134)
    - Infant Mortality, 1909 (Box 134)
    - Infantile Paralysis (Box 134)
    - Joint Application Bureau-.Minutes 1906-1916 (Box 135)
    - Joint Application Bureau 1904-1917 (General correspondence & memos; budget material; staff job description) (Box 135)
    - Joint Application Bureau:[indent]
      - 1904-1911 (Box 135)
      - 1907-1920 (Box 135)
      - Analysis of cases 1905-1906 (Box 135)
      - Definition of homeless men 1907 (Box 135)
      - Study of conditions in lodging houses 1912 (Box 135)
      - Study of conditions and working conditions in New Catskill Aqueduct 1911 (Box 135)
      - Annual Reports (Box 135)
      - Reports by contributors 1912-1920 (Box 135)
      - Early material has lists of staff members (Box 135)
      - 1908-1910 (Box 135)
      - January 1910-December 1912 (Box 136)
      - Reports on JAB casework at Municipal Lodging Houses (Box 136)
      - Reports by social secretary - Are Homeless men permanently made self supporting? (Box 136)
      - Outline - What a social workers job at the municipal lodging house should entail (Box 136)
      - December 1912-1913 (Box 136)
      - July 1912-March 1915 (Correspondence & brief progress reports indicate scope of Charles B. Barnes’ study of homeless men) (Box 136)
      - January1914-January 1917 (Box 136)
      - February-August 1920 (Services to ex-servicemen) (Box 136)
      - Budworth Case (Box 136)
      - Cooperative Workshop Plan 1934 (Box 137)
      - Study of the Homeless 1931, 1938 (Box 137)
    - Jones, John Price (Mr. Church) (Box 137)
    - Junior League 1910-30 (Box 137)
    - Junior League - Children's Scholarship 1930-1932 (Box 137)
    - Junior League - Assn. of (Box 137)
    - Junior League - Provisional Course (Box 137)
    - Junior Month See various Folders of samples of Student logs & evaluations kept for illustration of process rather than reference on individuals (Box 137)
    - Junior Month (Letters from Clare M. Tousley - show content & style of letter written to prospective & former Junior Month Students) (Box 137)
    - Junior Month:
      - College President's Letters (Box 137)
      - COS publicity (Box 137)
      - History & Sample Programs (Box 137)
      - Pictures (Box 137)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Bryn Mawr (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Valuations - Connecticut (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Elmira (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Goucher (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Mt. Holyoke (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Radcliffe (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Smith (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Swarthmore (Box 138)
      - Student Logs & Evaluations - Wellesley (Box 139)
      - Vassar (Box 139)
    - Kasius, Cora See: "Six Characters in Search of " ", 1925-Kasius (Box 139)
    - Kennedy Employment Service (Box 139)
    - Laundry 1894-1934 (Box 139)
    - Laundry 1905-1916 (not found, 10/1987) (Box 139)
    - Law Committee Legal Aid, Committee on (Box 139)
    - Legal Fees - 1913-1924 (Fees for legal service paid deForest Bros-legacy and corporate service) (Box 139)
    - Legal Questions (Box 139)
    - Legal Service (Box 140)
    - Legal Suggestions for Friendly Visitors (Box 140)
    - Legislation:
      - Admitting Children to Places of Amusement (Box 140)
      - Antin Bill (Box 140)
      - Child Labor Amendment (Box 140)
      - Child Marriage (Box 140)
      - Child Welfare Bill (Box 140)
      - City Bond Issue (Box 140)
      - Civil Rights Issue (Box 140)
      - Correspondence (Box 140)
      - Equal Rights for Women 1922-23 (Box 140)
      - Equal Rights for Women 1924 (Box 141)
      - Farm Colony - Vagrants (Box 141)
      - Feebleminded (Box 141)
      - Insanity Laws (Box 141)
      - Jury Trials (Box 141)
      - Kerr Bill - Immigration, Naturalization, Deportation (Box 141)
      - Marriage Laws (Box 141)
      - Legislation, 1902-1929 (Box 141)
      - Housing, 1913-1917 (Box 142)
      - New York State (Box 142)
      - New York State for Tuberculosis Care (Box 142)
    - Legislative Bills, 1912-1913 (Box 142)
    - Legislation, (6 Folders) (Box 142)
    - Lenox Hill (Box 143)
    - Lippincott, Earl (Box 143)
    - Liverpool (Box 143)
    - Lodging Houses (Box 143)
    - Lowell, Josephine Shaw, (7 Folders) (Box 143)
    - Lowell, Josephine Shaw, (2 Folders) (Box 144)
    - Lyons (Box 144)
    - Manhattan Trade School (Box 144)
    - Medical Exams (Box 144)
    - Mendicancy, 1883-1920 (See Also: Committees - Mendicancy; Vagrancy; NYC Police) (Box 144)
    - McLean Study of Queens. See: Queens Family Service. (Box 144)
    - Mental Health Clinic, Proposal for, 1925 (Box 144)
    - Merchants Association of New York, 1907-1925 (One of the early forerunners of National Information Bureau) (Box 144)
    - Merger Proposals, 1894, 1914, 1923 (Box 145)
    - Milford Conference (Box 145)
    - Milford Conference:
      - 11/30/32 - 6/30/33 (Box 145)
      - Final Report of the Committee of Five to the Milford Conference, November 1928 (Box 145)
      - Milford Conference minutes and reports, 1925 - 1934 (Box 145)
      - Milford Conference Report, 1928 and Minutes, 1933 (Box 145)
    - Milk Committee, 1907 (Box 146)
    - Milk Committee - New York, 1908-1915 (Box 146)
    - Milk Strike, 1916 - Effects of (Box 146)
    - Municipal Physicians and Nurses (Box 146)
    - Narcotics (Box 146)
    - National Alien Enemy Relief Committee (Box 147)
    - National Association of Societies for Organizing Charity (Important beginnings of Family Service Association of America) (Box 147)
    - National Child Labor Committee (Box 147)
    - National Committee for Mental Hygiene (Box 147)
    - National Conference of Charities & Correction 1897-1907 (Contains Theodore Roosevelt's signature (as Gov. of NYS); correspondence shows the variety of people and their interests who were invited to the National Conference) (Box 148)
    - National Dept, of Health (Concern re: Health here expressed pre-dates establishment of a United States Public Health Service or a Dept, of Health, Education and Welfare) (Box 148)